A Guide to the Pulaski Theater Oral Hisory Project 2003-2004
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Pulaski Theater Oral History Project 2003-04
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2004-007
2 containers, 0.75 cu. ft.
Collection contains 13 interview cassette tapes and 12 interview transcripts compiled by Dr. April Alen. In addition, the collection also includes the field notes and dissertation completed by Dr. Allen.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research with the exception of tapes and transcripts for which there are no oral history release forms. Folder 7 in box one and tapes 5 & 8 in box two are restricted with no access because release forms are unavailable for these interviews.
Acquisition Information
The Pulaski Theater Oral History Project was donated to Special Collections in 2004.
Biographical/Historical Information
The collection focuses on personal recollections of the Pulaski Theater, which operated from 1937 to 1991. Built in 1911, the structure initially hosted concerts and vaudevillian-style entertainment. However, the theater was closed in 1922 and remained a dry goods store until its reopening as a movie theater in 1937 under its new name--The Pulaski concerts. The interviewees are residents or former residents of Pulaski, VA with the memories of the building dating back to the original Elks Theater.
Scope and Content
The collection contains materials from 2003 to 2004 with the bulk from 2003. Collection consists of interview cassette tapes and transcripts of oral history interviews conducted in 2003 by April Allen, a PhD. candidate in the Interior Design Program within the College of Architecture and Urban Studies at Virginia Polytechnic Institute & State University. Interviewees include Ann King and Delores Brown, Betty Guynn, Marva Hickman, Edna Isbill, Lloyd Mathews, Bob and Sharon McKinney, George Penn, Wilmer and Ethel White. Transcripts available for all interviewees with the exception of Lloyd Mathews. The collection also includes Dr. Allen's field notes and her doctoral dissertation based on the Pulaski Theater located in Pulaski, VA.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by interviewee. Box 1 contains transcripts, field notes, and Dr. Allen's dissertation. Box 2 contains cassette tapes.
Contents List
- Pulaski Theater Oral History Project 2003-04
  - Ann King and Delores Brown interview transcript July 15, 2003 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Betty Guynn interview transcript June 19, 2003 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Marva Hickman interview transcript June 18, 2003 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Edna Isbill interview transcript July 15, 2003 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Sharon and Bob McKinney interview transcript July 22, 2003 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - George Penn interview transcript July 08, 2003 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Wilmer and Ethel Ryan interview transcript n.d. (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Seagle interview transcript June 11, 2003 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Pricilla Stith interview transcript June 04, 2003 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Keri Vass interview transcript June 19, 2003 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - John White interview transcript June 25, 2003 (Box-folder 1-11)
  - Walter White interview transcript July 08, 2003 (Box-folder 1-12)
  - Interview field notes n.d. (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Dr. April Allen's dissertation: "The Social Importance of a Small-town Theater: A Case Study of the Pulaski Theater, Pulaski, Virginia" © April 13, 2004 (Box-folder 1-14)
    Inventory available.
  - Interview cassette tapes n.d. (Box 2)
    Interview Cassette Tapes
    1. Ann King and Delores Brown
    2. Betty Guynn
    3. Betty Guynn
    4. Marva Hickman
    5. Edna Isbill
    6. Lloyd Mathews
    7. Sharon and Bob McKinney
    8. George Penn
    9. Wilmer and Ethel Ryan
    10. Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Seagle
    11. Pricilla Stith
    12. Keri Vass
    13. John White
    14. Walter White